<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "api.dtd">

<module name="pygame2.freetype.base">
  <alias>pygame2.freetype</alias>
  <short>Wrapping module for the FreeType 2 font library</short>
  <desc>
      This module allows for rendering all font formats supported by
      FreeType, namely TTF, Type1, CFF, OpenType, SFNT, PCF, FNT, BDF,
      PFR and Type42 fonts.

      This module is optional, and replaces all of the functionality of the
      original 'font' module, whilst expanding it. This module depends in no
      way on the SDL_ttf library.

      You should test that pygame.freetype is initialized before attempting
      to use the module; if the module is available and loaded, it will be
      automatically initialized by pygame.init()

      Most of the work done with fonts is done by using the actual Font objects.
      The module by itself only has routines to initialize itself and create
      Font objects with pygame.freetype.Font().

      You can load fonts from the system by using the pygame.freetype.SysFont()
      function. There are a few other functions to help lookup the system fonts.

      Pygame comes with a builtin default font. This can always be accessed by
      passing None as the font name to the Font constructor.
  </desc>
  <func name="get_error">
    <call>get_error() -> string</call>
    <desc>
        Returns the description of the last error which occurred in the
        FreeType library, or None if no errors have occurred.
    </desc>
  </func>

  <func name="get_version">
    <call>get_version() -> (int, int, int)</call>
    <desc>
        Gets the version of the FreeType2 library which was used to build
        the 'freetype' module.

        Note that the FreeType module depends on the FreeType 2 library,
        and will not compile with the original FreeType 1.0, hence the first
        element of the tuple will always be 2.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="init">
    <call>init(default_cache_size=64) -> None</call>
    <desc>
      Initializes the underlying FreeType 2 library.
      
      This function must be called before trying to use any of the functionality
      of the 'freetype' module. It is safe to call this function more than once.

      Optionally, you may specify a default size for the Glyph cache:
      this is the maximum amount of glyphs that will be cached at any
      given time by the module.
      Exceedingly small values will be automatically tuned for performance.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="quit">
    <call>quit() -> None</call>
    <desc>
      Shuts down the underlying FreeType 2 library.

      After calling this function, you should not invoke any class,
      method or function related to the 'freetype' module as they are likely to
      fail or might give unpredictable results. It is safe to call this function
      even if the module hasn't been initialized yet.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="was_init">
    <call>was_init() -> bool</call>
    <desc>
      Returns whether the the FreeType 2 library is initialized.
    </desc>
  </func>


  <class name="Font">
    <constructor>Font (file [, ptsize, style, index]) -> Font</constructor>
    <desc>
        Creates a new Font from a supported font file.

        *file* can be either a string representing the font's filename,
        a file-like object containing the font, or None; in this last case
        the default, built-in font will be used.

        Optionally, a *ptsize* argument may be specified to set the
        default size in points which will be used to render the font. 
        Such size can also be specified manually on each method call.
        Because of the way the caching system works, specifying a
        default size on the constructor doesn't imply a performance
        gain over manually passing the size on each function call.

        If the font file has more than one face, the *index* argument
        may be specified to specify which face index to load. Defaults
        to 0; font loading will fail if the given index is not contained
        in the font.

        The 'style' argument will set the default style (italic,
        underline, bold) used to draw this font. This style may be
        overriden on any Font.render() call.
    </desc>
    <attr name="name">
      <desc>Read only. Gets the name of the font face.</desc>
    </attr>
    <method name="get_size">
      <call>get_size(text [, style, rotation, ptsize]) -> int, int</call>
      <desc>
          Gets the size in pixels which 'text' will occupy when rendered
          using this Font. The calculations will take into account the
          font's default style (e.g. underlined fonts take extra height
          for the underline), or the style may be overriden by the
          'style' parameter.

          Returns a tuple containing the width and height of the text's
          bounding box. 
          
          The calculations are done using the font's default size in points,
          without any rotation, and taking into account fonts which are set
          to be drawn vertically via the Font.vertical attribute.
          Optionally you may specify another point size to use via the
          'ptsize' argument, or a text rotation via the 'rotation' argument.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_metrics">
      <call>get_metrics(text, [bbmode, ptsize]) -> [(...), ...]</call>
      <desc>
        Returns the glyph metrics for each character in 'text'.

        The glyph metrics are returned inside a list; each character will
        be represented as a tuple inside the list with the following values:

          (min_x, max_x, min_y, max_y, horizontal_advance)

        By default, these values are returned as grid-fitted pixel
        coordinates (ints). Optionally, one of the following constants
        (which can be found on the FreeType constants module) may be passed
        as the bbmode argument:

            BBOX_EXACT: Return accurate floating point values.

            BBOX_EXACT_GRIDFIT: Return accurate floating point values aligned
            to the drawing grid.

            BBOX_PIXEL: Return pixel coordinates (ints).

            BBOX_PIXEL_GRIDFIT (default): Return grid-aligned pixel coordinates.
        
        The calculations are done using the font's default size in points.
        Optionally you may specify another point size to use.

      </desc>
    </method>
    <attr name="height">
      <desc>Read only. Gets the height of the Font. This is the average
      value of all glyphs in the font.</desc>
    </attr>
    <method name="render">
      <call>render(dest, text, fgcolor [, bgcolor, style, rotation, ptsize]) -> int, int[, :class:`pygame2.sdl.video.Surface`]</call>
      <desc>
        Renders a text on a SDL surface.

        Renders the string *text* to a
        :class:`pygame2.sdl.video.Surface`, using the color *fgcolor*.

        The *dest* parameter is supposed to be a tuple containing
        the surface and the coordinates at which the text will be rendered,
        in that order.

        If such tuple exists, and the destination surface is a valid
        :class:`pygame2.sdl.video.Surface` (independently of its bit
        depth), the text will be rendered directly on top of it at the
        passed coordinates, using the given *fgcolor*, and painting
        the background of the text with the given 'bgcolor', if available. 
        The alpha values for both colors are always taken into account.
        The width and height of the rendered text will be returned in a tuple.

        If 'None' is passed instead of the destination tuple, a new 32 bit
        :class:`pygame2.sdl.video.Surface` will be created with the
        required size to contain the drawn text, and using *bgcolor* as its
        background color. If a background color is not available, the 
        surface will be filled with zero alpha opacity.
        The width and height of the rendered text,
        together with the new :class:`pygame2.sdl.video.Surface`, will
        be returned in a tuple.

        The rendering is done using the font's default size in points
        and its default style, without any rotation, and taking into
        account fonts which are set to be drawn vertically via the
        Font.vertical attribute.
        
        Optionally you may specify another point size to use via the
        'ptsize' argument, a text rotation via the 'rotation' argument,
        or a new text style via the 'style' argument.

        This function is only available when PyGame 2 has been compiled
        with SDL support.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="render_raw">
      <call>render_raw(text [, ptsize]) -> int, int, bytes</call>
      <desc>
        Renders a text to a byte buffer.

        Renders the string *text* to a raw buffer of bytes, each byte
        representing the opacity of the glyph's raster image in
        grayscale.
        
        The width (pitch) and height of the rendered text, together with
        the bytes buffer, will be returned in a tuple.

        The rendering is done using the font's default size in points.
        Optionally you may specify another point size to use.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <attr name="style">
        <desc>
            Gets or sets the default style of the Font. This default style
            will be used for all text rendering and size calculations unless
            overriden specifically in the `render()` or `get_size()` calls.
            The style value may be a bitwise OR of one or more of the following
            constants:
                
                STYLE_NONE
                STYLE_UNDERLINE
                STYLE_ITALIC
                STYLE_BOLD

            These constants may be found on the FreeType constants module.
            Optionally, the default style can be modified or obtained
            accessing the individual style attributes (underline, italic,
            bold).
      </desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="underline">
      <desc>
        Gets or sets whether the font will be underlined when drawing text.
        This default style value will be used for all text rendering and 
        size calculations unless overriden specifically in the `render()` 
        or `get_size()` calls, via the 'style' parameter.
      </desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="bold">
      <desc>
        Gets or sets whether the font will be bold when drawing text.
        This default style value will be used for all text rendering and 
        size calculations unless overriden specifically in the `render()` 
        or `get_size()` calls, via the 'style' parameter.
      </desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="italic">
      <desc>
        Gets or sets whether the font will be slanted when drawing text.
        This default style value will be used for all text rendering and 
        size calculations unless overriden specifically in the `render()` 
        or `get_size()` calls, via the 'style' parameter.
      </desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="fixed_width">
      <desc>
        Read only. Returns whether this Font is a fixed-width (bitmap) font.
        
        .. note::
        
          Note that scalable fonts whose glyphs are all the same width 
          (i.e. monospace TTF fonts used for programming) are not considered
          fixed width.
      </desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="antialiased">
      <desc>
          Gets or sets the font's antialiasing mode. This defaults to True
          on all fonts, which will be rendered by default antialiased.

          Setting this to true will change all rendering methods to use
          glyph bitmaps without antialiasing, which supposes a small speed gain
          and a significant memory gain because of the way glyphs are cached.
      </desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="vertical">
      <desc>
          Gets or sets whether the font is a vertical font such as fonts
          representing Kanji glyphs or other styles of vertical writing.

          Changing this attribute will cause the font to be rendering
          vertically, and affects all other methods which manage glyphs
          or text layouts to use vertical metrics accordingly.

          Note that the FreeType library doesn't automatically detect
          whether a font contains glyphs which are always supposed to
          be drawn vertically, so this attribute must be set manually
          by the user.

          Also note that several font formats (specially bitmap based
          ones) don't contain the necessary metrics to draw glyphs
          vertically, so drawing in those cases will give unspecified
          results.
      </desc>
    </attr>
  </class>
  
</module>

