<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "api.dtd">

<module name="pygame2.resources">
  <short>Resource management methods.</short>
  <desc>
    Resource management methods.
  </desc>
  
  <class name="Resources">
    <constructor>Resources () -> Resources</constructor>
    <desc>Creates a new resource container instance.
    
      The Resources class manages a set of file resources and eases accessing
      them by using relative paths, scanning archives automatically and so on.
    </desc>
    <method name="add">
      <call>add (filename) -> None</call>
      <desc>Adds a file to the Resources container.

        Depending on the file type (determined by the file suffix or name),
        the file will be automatically scanned (if it is an archive) or
        checked for availability (if it is a stream/network resource).
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="add_archive">
      <call>add_archive (self, filename, typehint='zip') -> None</call>
      <desc>Adds an archive file to the Resources container.

        This will scan the passed archive and add its contents to the list
        of available resources.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="add_file">
      <call>add_file (self, filename) -> None</call>
      <desc>Adds a file to the Resources container.

        This will only add the passed file and do not scan an archive or check
        a stream for availability.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get">
      <call>get (filename) -> StringIO or BytesIO</call>
      <desc>Gets a specific file from the Resources.

        Raises a KeyError, if *filename* could not be found.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_filelike">
      <call>get_filelike (filename) -> file or StringIO or BytesIO</call>
      <desc>
        Like get(), but tries to return the original file handle, if possible.

        If the passed *filename* is only available within an archive, a
        StringIO instance will be returned.

        Raises a KeyError, if *filename* could not be found.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_path">
      <call>get_path (filename) -> str</call>
      <desc>Gets the path of the passed filename.

        If *filename* is only available within an archive, a string in the form
        'filename@archivename' will be returned.

        Raises a KeyError, if *filename* could not be found.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="scan">
      <call>scan (path) -> None</call>
      <desc>Scans a path and adds all found files to the Resource container.

        Scans a path and adds all found files to the Resource container. If a
        file is a supported (ZIP or TAR) archive, its contents will be indexed
        and added automatically.

        *excludepattern* can be a regular expression to skip files, which match
        the pattern.
      </desc>
    </method>
  </class>

  <func name="open_tarfile">
    <call>open_tarfile (archive, filename, dir=None, type=None) -> StringIO or BytesIO</call>
    <desc>Opens and reads a certain file from a TAR archive.

      Opens and reads a certain file from a TAR archive. The result is returned
      as StringIO stream. *filename* can be a relative or absolute path within
      the ZIP archive. The optional *dir* argument can be used to supply a
      relative directory path, under which *filename* will be tried to retrieved.

      *type* is used to supply additional compression information, in case the
      system cannot determine the compression type itself, and can be either
      'gz' for gzip compression or 'bz2' for bzip2 compression.

      .. note::

        If *type* is supplied, the compreesion mode will be enforced for opening
        and reading.

      If the *filename* could not be found or an error occured on reading it,
      None will be returned.

      Raises a TypeError, if *archive* is not a valid TAR archive or if *type*
      is not a valid value of ('gz', 'bz2').
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="open_url">
    <call>open_url (filename, basepath=None) -> file</call>
    <desc>Opens and reads a certain file from a web or remote location.

      Opens and reads a certain file from a web or remote location. This function
      utilizes the urllib2 module, which means that it is restricted to the types
      of remote locations supported by urllib2.

      *basepath* can be used to supply an additional location prefix.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="open_zipfile">
    <call>open_zipfile (archive, filename, dir=None) -> StringIO or BytesIO</call>
    <desc>Opens and reads a certain file from a ZIP archive.

      Opens and reads a certain file from a ZIP archive. The result is returned
      as StringIO stream. *filename* can be a relative or absolute path within
      the ZIP archive. The optional *dir* argument can be used to supply a
      relative directory path, under which *filename* will be tried to retrieved.

      If the *filename* could not be found or an error occured on reading it,
      None will be returned.

      Raises a TypeError, if *archive* is not a valid ZIP archive.
    </desc>
  </func>
</module>

