<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE module SYSTEM "api.dtd">

<module name="pygame2.sdl.joystick">
  <short>SDL joystick I/O wrapper wrapper module</short>
  <desc>
    The joystick module manages the joystick devices on a computer
    (there can be more than one). Joystick devices include trackballs
    and video-game-style gamepads, and the module allows the use of
    multiple buttons and "hats".
  </desc>

  <class name="Joystick">
    <constructor>Joystick (index) -> Joystick</constructor>
    <desc>
      Creates a new Joystick object for the specified physical device.
      
      The Joystick object allows you to access information about the
      underlying physical device, such as the axes, hats and button
      states.
      
      The *index* must be in the range [0,
      :meth:`pygame2.sdl.joystick.num_joysticks` - 1].  This will also
      open the Joystick initially.
    </desc>
    <method name="close">
      <call>close () -> None</call>
      <desc>
        Closes the access to the underlying joystick device.
        
        Calling or accessing any other method or attribute of the
        Joystick after closing it will cause an exception to be
        thrown. To reaccess the Joystick, you have to :meth:`open` it
        again.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_axis">
      <call>get_axis (index) -> int</call>
      <desc>
        Gets the current position of the specified axis.
        
        Gets the current position of the specified axis. The axis *index*
        must be a valid value within the range [0, :attr:`num_axes` - 1].
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_ball">
      <call>get_ball (index) -> int, int</call>
      <desc>
        Gets the relative movement of a trackball.

        Gets the relative movement of a trackball since the last call to
        get_ball. The ball *index* must be a valid value within the range
        [0, :attr:`num_balls` - 1].
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_button">
      <call>get_button (index) -> bool</call>
      <desc>
        Gets the state of a button.
        
        Gets the current pressed state of a button. The button *index* 
        must be a valid value within the range [0, :attr:`num_buttons` - 1].
      </desc>
    </method>
    <method name="get_hat">
      <call>get_hat (index) -> int</call>
      <desc>
        Gets the state of a hat.
        
        Gets the current state of a hat. The return value will be a
        bitwise OR'd combination of the hat constants as specified in the 
        :mod:`pygame2.sdl.constants` module. The hat *index* must be a valid
        value within the range [0, :attr:`num_hats` - 1].
      </desc>
    </method>
    <attr name="index">
      <desc>Gets the physical device index of the Joystick.</desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="name">
      <desc>Gets the physical device name of the Joystick.</desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="num_axes">
      <desc>Gets the number of axes available on the Joystick.</desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="num_balls">
      <desc>Gets the number of balls available on the Joystick.</desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="num_buttons">
      <desc>Gets the number of buttons available on the Joystick.</desc>
    </attr>
    <attr name="num_hats">
      <desc>Gets the number of hats available on the Joystick.</desc>
    </attr>
    <method name="open">
      <call>open () -> None</call>
      <desc>
        Opens the (closed) Joystick.
        
        Opens the (closed) Joystick. If the Joystick is already open,
        this method will have no effect.
      </desc>
    </method>
    <attr name="opened">
      <desc>Gets, whether the Joystick is open or not.</desc>
    </attr>
  </class>

  <func name="get_name">
    <call>get_name (index) -> str</call>
    <desc>
      Gets the physical device name of a Joystick.
      
      Gets the physical device name of a Joystick. The *index* specifies
      the device to get the name for and must be in the range [0,
      :meth:`num_joysticks` - 1].
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="init">
    <call>init () -> None</call>
    <desc>
      Initializes the joystick subsystem of the SDL library.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="num_joysticks">
    <call>num_joysticks () -> int</call>
    <desc>
      Gets the number of detected and available joysticks for the system.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="opened">
    <call>opened (index) -> bool</call>
    <desc>
      Gets, whether the specified Joystick is opened for access or not.
      
      Gets, whether the specified Joystick is opened for access or
      not. The *index* specifies the joystick device to get the state for
      and must be in the range [0, :meth:`num_joysticks` - 1].
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="quit">
    <call>quit () -> None</call>
    <desc>
      Shuts down the joystick subsystem of the SDL library.

      Shuts down the joystick subsystem of the SDL library and closes all
      existing Joystick objects (leaving them intact).
      
      After calling this function, you should not invoke any class,
      method or function related to the joystick subsystem as they are
      likely to fail or might give unpredictable results.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="event_state">
    <call>event_state (state) -> int</call>
    <desc>
      Enables or disable joystick event polling.
      
      Enables or disables joystick event processing. If the joystick
      event processing is disabled, you will have to update the joystick
      states manually using :meth:`update` and read the information
      manually using the specific attributes and methods. Otherwise,
      joystick events are consumed and process by the
      :mod:`pygame2.sdl.event` module.
      
      The *state* argument can be :const:`ENABLE` or :const:`IGNORE` for
      enabling or disabling the event processing or :const:`QUERY` to receive
      the current state. The return value also will be one of those three
      constants.
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="update">
    <call>update () -> None</call>
    <desc>
      Updates the joystick states (in case event processing is disabled).
    </desc>
  </func>
  <func name="was_init">
    <call>was_init () -> bool</call>
    <desc>
      Returns, whether the joystick subsystem of the SDL library is
      initialized.
    </desc>
  </func>
</module>

